So now we have seen how to create, read and update classic one cards.
We will see how to do update on Mifare Classic 4K cards.
Although both cards are very similar and the only difference is the memory size.
So.
Uh, let's just open our PDF for Mifare classic 4k cards as well.
So this is our PDF for 4k card.
Let me open it over here.
So let me make it a little zoom.
So the only difference with classic one and 4K cards is the memory size.
So over here you can see there are, uh.
63 address blocks in one K and in a classic 4k.
There are 255 address blocks.
All right, so.
We will write and from block 31 or sorry, 32 till 40.
Or 39.
All the blocks contains 16.
All the sectors contains 16 blocks.
Before that, all the blocks are same as the classic one card.
So we will pick any any block and we will write data.
So let's just pick some block from.
Let's just choose sector 32 and address 128.
Now, let's let me remind one more time this address is in hexadecimal.
Sorry, this address is in decimal.
You have to convert this address into hexadecimal.
So let's just convert 128 into hexadecimal.
So 128 is equal to 80 in hexadecimal.
And let's just check what's 255 so 255 is F, so 128 is 80.
So we will just, uh, write some data on this card.
So let me remove my one card first.
And let me play for Cape Cod.
So let's just do our connection one more time.
And let's just read that data to get the.
So you can see the over here and let's just do get HDR and.
4K card also comes with the default transport configuration, as you can see.
And over here you can see my classic 4K written and let's just authenticate block zero, you know,
just check the Uid.
So let's just do authenticate blog zero Read Block zero.
And over here you can compare the.
It's the same over here.
So Block Zero contains the Uuid and the manufacturers data, as we discussed previously.
So now we have to write some data on block 80, which is 128 in hexadecimal.
So let's just authenticate.
Block 80.
With key zero or key A, which is the default key and saying authentication success.
Let's just read data.
And all the zeros.
We can write any data over here.
Write some simple data.
And let's just do.
Okay?
Write binary block success.
Let's just read this data.
And ski.
So you can see some data, some sample data.
Right.
So this is how you read, right?
4K cards as well.
So if you have 4K cards, you can use 4K cards.
And if you have one card, you can use one cards.
Both cards are similar.
The only difference is the memory size.
The memory size of 4K is bigger than one K.
It depends on your application and it depends on client requirement, what type of card you want to
use.
But for technical purpose, both the cards are similar as far as considering reading, writing and updating
the keys.
This card is similar to one K card.
Right?
So I'll I'm not going to repeat all the things which I have done for the one K card.
As a practice, you can do all the things on 4k cards as well, right?
So this is how you read, write, update the keys and write data and create value blocks in classic
cards in the next video or in the next section, we are going to see how to read, write and update
data and how to update the keys as well and create the value blocks.
All these things.
We are going to see how to do these things using the RC module with Stm8 microcontrollers.
So MF RC 5 to 2 two module.
There is a special module from IC station which we are going to use in our next section that that has
a built in microcontroller with the RC 5 to 2 chip and the microcontroller chip are on the same board.
We are going to use that module and we will see all these operations on that board and see how to update
a classic card using that board.